<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machinima For Dummies - The Blog Of The Book</title>
    <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Machinima For Dummies - The Blog Of The Book</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 20:26:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.machinimafordummies.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Source Filmmaker Out, free for COMMERCIAL use</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2012/06/27/source-filmmaker-out-free-for-commercial-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 20:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2012/06/27/source-filmmaker-out-free-for-commercial-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Holy crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sourcefilmmaker.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.sourcefilmmaker.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that makes the discussion about which engine to use all the more interesting…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Crazed Stalkers! </title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2011/01/26/get-crazed-stalkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 17:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2011/01/26/get-crazed-stalkers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first big Guerilla Showrunner project is now up and available, and I&amp;rsquo;m thinking a lot of Machinima people will find it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about what makes a series project fun, and the answer that came back was - fans. Active fans who comment on the show, tell you they like it, and tell their friends about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too often we end up with thousands of casual viewers whom we only know as numbers on a YouTube page, and not as many interested, involved viewers as we&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of thinking about this, and I&amp;rsquo;ve come to the conclusion that a lot of that is, frankly, down to us as showrunners. We control a lot of what makes people either stay and become fans or leave and never come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I made a video course about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about half an hour in total, split up into three lessons. In the first one, I talk about quick, simple things that we can do - but often fail to - to increase the number of people who become fans of our shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part 2, I talk about how to design a show so that it fascinates people and makes them come back again and again. And in the third part…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, in the third part I basically talk about how to become a rock star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the course over here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[](&lt;a href=&#34;http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/)[http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/](http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/&#34;&gt;http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/)[http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/](http://guerillashowrunner.com/crazed-stalkers-free/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s totally free, and I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to hearing what people think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look, new &#34;Guerilla Showrunner&#34; blog - plus, MfD&#39;s future</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2011/01/07/hugh-announces-new-teaching-blog-plus-whats-happening-with-mfd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 18:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2011/01/07/hugh-announces-new-teaching-blog-plus-whats-happening-with-mfd/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s the Day of Announcements here at Machinima for Dummies Towers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;guerilla-showrunner&#34;&gt;Guerilla Showrunner!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new project - yes, in addition to the mammoth task that is Death Knight Love Story. For a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling I want to do a bit more talking about all the various tips and tricks I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over more than a decade of making shows. And I&amp;rsquo;m not just talking about Machinima shows here, but also live-action stuff like Kamikaze Cookery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it occurred to me that no-one&amp;rsquo;s really talking about the new paradigm in showrunning. Traditionally, a &amp;ldquo;Showrunner&amp;rdquo; is someone like Joss Whedon or JJ Abrams - the guy running the entire, enormous, expensive apperatus of a full-fledged network TV show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these days, technology&amp;rsquo;s done to that idea what it&amp;rsquo;s done to film, to music, and to publishing. Nowadays, you can be - and I have been, multiple times, and so have a lot of you guys - a showrunner from your bedroom, with a budget in the tens of dollars rather than the tens of millions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to acknowledge that, come together, and start talking about how we make Our Thing - our tiny-budget serialised video thing - work. And so I&amp;rsquo;ve been starting to write some of the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve learned down, in the hopes that it&amp;rsquo;ll help other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guerillashowrunner.com&#34;&gt;Guerilla Showrunner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve got articles on &lt;a href=&#34;http://guerillashowrunner.com/2010/11/3-ways-to-get-more-viewers-right-the-fuck-now/&#34;&gt;how to get more viewers&lt;/a&gt;, why you &lt;a href=&#34;http://guerillashowrunner.com/2010/11/big-scary-plan/&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t actually need a big scary plan for your show&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://guerillashowrunner.com/2010/11/wtf-is-a-funnel/&#34;&gt;what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about when I say &amp;ldquo;Funnel&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, and why it&amp;rsquo;s vital for your viewer numbers, and today I&amp;rsquo;ve just put a piece up about &lt;a href=&#34;http://guerillashowrunner.com/2011/01/whats-your-goal-for-your-show-probably-not-what-you-think-it-is/&#34;&gt;how to make sure you know what your show&amp;rsquo;s goals are&lt;/a&gt; (because it&amp;rsquo;s easy to screw up if you don&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also just finishing off a free course on &lt;a href=&#34;http://guerillashowrunner.com/get-more-crazed-stalkers-the-free-course/&#34;&gt;converting casual viewers to crazed fans&lt;/a&gt;, but more info on that when it&amp;rsquo;s ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-mfd-too&#34;&gt;And MfD too&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnnie and I have also been talking about what we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing with MfD in the New Year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, expect a new layout and backend pretty soon. That should deal with the spammer problems that have afflicted us, and generally drag the site kicking and screaming into the &amp;lsquo;10s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Machinima world&amp;rsquo;s pretty quiet right now, but we&amp;rsquo;re also looking at what sort of things we can blog about in the New Year. There are some exciting tech developments coming up - Kinect, anyone? - which we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering, and maybe getting a bit more codey and hacky than we usually do. We&amp;rsquo;re also going to be looking at the fact that the Machinima world&amp;rsquo;s really split apart, and seeing what we can do to start us all trading ideas again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we might even end up doing some ebooks or something similar, covering developments and techniques that have happened since the book was published 4 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcement: Johnnie no longer works for Moviestorm Ltd.</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2011/01/07/announcement-johnnie-no-longer-works-for-moviestorm-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 13:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2011/01/07/announcement-johnnie-no-longer-works-for-moviestorm-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick announcement, in the spirit of full disclosure: as of January 2011, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moviestorm.co.uk/forums/index.php?s=0&amp;amp;showtopic=10367&#34;&gt;I am no longer employed by Moviestorm Ltd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know we&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty quiet on this blog recently. Sorry about that. Both Hugh and I have been pretty busy, and the blog has been drowned in spam, but we&amp;rsquo;ve got some exciting changes planned. I&amp;rsquo;ll let Hugh tell you more about that in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryzom - MMORPG goes totally open-source</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/05/06/ryzom-mmorpg-goes-totally-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 16:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/05/06/ryzom-mmorpg-goes-totally-open-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In what must be one of the most potentially exciting developments for independent machinima creators in a long time, we&amp;rsquo;ve just heard that Winch Gate Properties Ltd., the creators of the online MMORPG &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryzom.com/&#34;&gt;Ryzom&lt;/a&gt;, will be releasing the entire game as an open-source project. It sounds like the developers are keen to work with the community, and will be accepting the best 3rd-party developments into the main Ryzom codebase. Projects already underway include ports of the game to both Mac OSX and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is fabulous news for machinima and anymation. An open-source licence like this gives the double benefit of a game that&amp;rsquo;s easy to modify (because the entire source code can be studied and adapted) and a game without the usual copyright restrictions on use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for both the game client and server, as well as several content creation tools, will be released under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.html&#34;&gt;GNU Affero GPL&lt;/a&gt; licence. The assets (textures, sounds, etc) will be under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution Share-Alike&lt;/a&gt; licence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to be honest now and say that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Ryzom before this announcement, but I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be taking a look now! Open-sourcing a game like this is an incredibly bold move, which deserves the highest praise. It&amp;rsquo;s crucial that we take advantage of the opportunity, and use this resource to create things which Winch Gate could never have imagined. In doing so, we validate their decision to release the code, we provide exciting tools and assets for the rest of the community to use, and we&amp;rsquo;ll have yet another tool in our anymation library. Although Ryzom is not the most graphically sophisticated game on the market, the flexibility of an open-source codebase more than make up for that. So, here&amp;rsquo;s a challenge to the community: go make something cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dev.ryzom.com/news/13&#34;&gt;Original press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moviestorm Lifetime Subscriptions </title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/04/26/moviestorm-lifetime-subscriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 19:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/04/26/moviestorm-lifetime-subscriptions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As promised last year, Moviestorm have now announced lifetime subscriptions, for f Â£149.99 / â‚¬199.99 / $249.99 .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good stuff. Now, we&amp;rsquo;re just waiting for that end-of-life policy…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moviestorm does sex - what we think.</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/04/08/moviestorm-does-sex-what-we-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 14:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/04/08/moviestorm-does-sex-what-we-think/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Damn those guys at Moviestorm. They&amp;rsquo;re the only software company doing really interesting things with Machinima right now (the Second Life pro-Machinima EULA change nonwithstanding - I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about that later - and iClone people, if you have interesting news, please send it to us!), and so we at MfD have to keep writing our big &amp;ldquo;yes, we&amp;rsquo;ve both done work for them, Johnnie&amp;rsquo;s their product manager, but Hugh&amp;rsquo;s writing this as an independent outsider&amp;rdquo; disclaimer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have they done this time? They&amp;rsquo;ve earned my eternal respect by being the first Machinima tool developer ever to realise that people might want to make films about people having sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I know SL has plenty of sex. But they&amp;rsquo;ve never released a &amp;ldquo;Sex Island&amp;rdquo; pack. It&amp;rsquo;s a very brave move for a company to release an official pack supporting sexuality.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get started, a disclaimer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-article-will-explicitly-discuss-sex-and-sexuality-you-have-been-warned&#34;&gt;THIS ARTICLE WILL EXPLICITLY DISCUSS SEX AND SEXUALITY. YOU HAVE BEEN WARNED.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t usually do R-rated here at MfD, but this is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;after-dark&#34;&gt;After Dark!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories are about sex and death. That&amp;rsquo;s basically it for humans&amp;rsquo; interest in narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Violence is easy. We&amp;rsquo;ve had it in Machinima since Diary of a Camper. Indeed, one of the advantages of Machinima that I and others have touted is that it makes it easy to make films with spectacular violence in them, very cheaply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sex, not so much. We&amp;rsquo;ve spoken on MfD before about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.machinimafordummies.com/articles/2009/07/08/porn-and-expression-two-pieces-of-evidence-for-machinima-development&#34;&gt;wierd &amp;ldquo;porn gap&amp;rdquo; in Machinima &lt;/a&gt;- until recently, there was very little porn being produced in the medium at all. And Machinima films rarely feature sexuality in any way - romance, sure, but sex, desire, bodies, flesh, hardly ever. Why? Well, partially because it&amp;rsquo;s not really a strength of the medium, partially because there&amp;rsquo;s long been a feeling that if you want to make porn, you&amp;rsquo;re better making it in real life, and partially because there weren&amp;rsquo;t graphical assets to support it. After all, given the trouble Mass Effect got into for a very short, non-explicit sex scene, which major games company wants to go there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter Moviestorm, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moviestorm.co.uk/moviestorm/after_dark&#34;&gt;their new After Dark pack&lt;/a&gt;, which includes nude skins with morphable breasts and genitals, and explicit oral and other penetrative sex animations. We&amp;rsquo;ve never seen something this explicit outside &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.3dkink.com/3d/&#34;&gt;dedicated sex simulators&lt;/a&gt; (link VERY NSFW) or user-generated Second Life content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tracked CEO Jeff Zie down to ask him about the basis behind this rather ballsy (sorry) move. He&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear about his intentions with this pack - &amp;ldquo;After Dark is a toe in the water to see how a (currently) small user-base responds. From a content perspective, it broadens any film-maker&amp;rsquo;s range, and it&amp;rsquo;s entirely optional. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect everyone to be putting sex and nudity into their content. But maybe some will. Let&amp;rsquo;s see, before we&amp;rsquo;re massively mainstream.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that there was a certain amount of trepidation at Moviestorm about the user reactions to the pack - however, from a read of the major thread on the forums about the pack, the reaction has actually mostly been positive. The two major objections that have been raised that the development time could have been used to improve modding tools for Moviestorm, and that the actual animations in the pack were rather porn-focussed, rather than romantic, and more focussed on male pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;but-you-could-have-supported-modders&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;But you could have supported modders&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument about development time is a little simplistic. From talking to Jeff, the major hurdles to enabling more user-generated content in Moviestorm are legal rather than technological: &amp;ldquo;Enabling this stuff&amp;rsquo;s the easy bit. The hard bit is quality control, technical integrity - and most importantly - IP ownership.&amp;rdquo; He&amp;rsquo;s concerned that UGC directly sold through Moviestorm - which is obviously the only way it&amp;rsquo;ll generate the company revenue directly - might open Moviestorm up to legal liability, and so is seeking legal clarification on those points. As he says, obviously that&amp;rsquo;s not something that Moviestorm&amp;rsquo;s artists and programmers can help with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also mentions that the other significant barrier to enabling more user-generated content would be quality control and testing. &amp;ldquo;I want to be able to give both customers and commercial partners a great experience. That&amp;rsquo;s part of the DNA of a world-class brand and service. I think Moviestorm needs to be able to have that ability.&amp;rdquo; Jeff&amp;rsquo;s argument is that, whilst big brands like Unreal and the Source engine are able to enable very free-and-easy modding, for Moviestorm user-created content is much closer to the core of the brand, and bad content might negatively affect MS&amp;rsquo;s reputation. Games make their money from games sales, and modding is &amp;ldquo; for a &lt;em&gt;tiny&lt;/em&gt; minority of their customer-base.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial reaction to this approach was distinctly skeptical. On the one hand, with the recession biting, Moviestorm clearly needs to concentrate hard on revenue generation, and the only way to do that with user-generated content is to sell it through a marketplace and take a slice of the revenue. At that point, of course, quality and legal issues come into play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, having access to MS skeletons and being able to create a full range of new content would significantly increase the value of Moviestorm as a filmmaking tool, and would probably spark a much wider range of free content. Before the change to a non-free model, there were obvious problems with that approach, namely that Moviestorm would be enabling their own competition. However, now, as many people have said, its hard to see why giving Moviestorm modders more tools wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a good longer-term call, assuming that there weren&amp;rsquo;t significant technical problems with doing so. Whilst Jeff makes reference to IP problems, the model of many, many games engines seems to imply that would almost certainly not apply to modding outside MS&amp;rsquo;s control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So are there technical issues? I talked to Chris Ollis, lead artist at Moviestorm, and he referenced a couple of problems with releasing more modding tools, including the increased support overhead. That&amp;rsquo;s a real concern - no matter how much MS says &amp;ldquo;these tools aren&amp;rsquo;t officially supported&amp;rdquo;, additional support requests will still happen. (That&amp;rsquo;s something else we can learn from the games companies&amp;rsquo; example). According to Chris and Johnnie, there are also some significant hurdles beyond just packaging up the 3DS Max assets used for Moviestorm - Johnnie says &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a LOT of stuff to be done to get the skeletons into a format that will be of any use at all outside this building.&amp;rdquo;, whilst Chris referenced a lot of specific details that need to be right for assets to work in MS, like specific poses, custom bones with very specific purposes, skin weightings, and other things that would all have to be documented - a non-zero cost. I&amp;rsquo;ve done enough work with games company assets to know that the skeleton would probably require a 20,000 word document accompanying it, and would still generate a large number of support requests. That&amp;rsquo;s probably enough work that it&amp;rsquo;s hard, given that Moviestorm is definitely in search of profitability at this point, to justify spending business hours on it at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, then, it looks like modding tools aren&amp;rsquo;t being held up for screwing animations, so much as they&amp;rsquo;re being held up for lack of a viable business case. That&amp;rsquo;s disappointing for modders, but fairly reasonable for Moviestorm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-are-the-lesbians&#34;&gt;Where are the lesbians?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pack includes doggy-style sex animations, blowjob animations, and sex on a table. The choice of animations has come in for a bit of stick on the forums, notably from Kate Fosk, who said &amp;ldquo;I think this pack suffers more than most from the lack of a female viewpoint, there&amp;rsquo;s an icky feel to it which doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit with the rest of the product.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a personal standpoint, the animations available aren&amp;rsquo;t the ones I&amp;rsquo;d chose for a pack like this either. I&amp;rsquo;m surprised by the lack of woman-on-top, about the only sex position which is really usable across the range from comparatively mainstream Hollywood movies to hardcore porn. My inner feminist was also a bit disappointed by the lack of oral sex for woman as well as men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently the content of the pack was largely chosen in group meetings, with the final say going to Chris Ollis, Head of Art at Moviestorm. Given this was a test pack, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of art time available for the assets, and so they were apparently chosen for a wide variety of considerations including taste, similar animations elsewhere, and practical speed of animation. Chris says that the animations deliberately don&amp;rsquo;t include accurate penetration, &amp;ldquo; to avoid people filming overly graphic close-ups.&amp;rdquo;. There was no missionary sex because &amp;ldquo;we allude to that in the bedroom pack so it would have been wasting time/repetition&amp;rdquo; or kissing and cuddling because &amp;ldquo;it was a test sex pack, not an intmate romance one&amp;rdquo;. Woman on top apparently missed the cut by a whisker, and would have been the next animation created. As to the animations that did make it in, Johnnie says &amp;ldquo;What eventually was released was influenced by how practically easy the animation was to implement&amp;rdquo; - it&amp;rsquo;s notable that doggy-style and male oral involve very little body interaction. The deciding factor appears to have been that all the animations are also usable for M/M sex - whilst I applaud that, I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure how much use it will get outside comedy from Moviestorm users, but we shall see. It&amp;rsquo;s a brave move to offer M/M gay sex rather than F/F, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of the pack appears to be rather specific: Jeff, Chris and the After Dark page all agree that the intention is to allow filmmakers to create very edgy, sexually-explicit films that are nonetheless within the mainstream, a la Straw Dogs, Romance, or Brokeback Mountain. (That fits with the decision to allow M/M rather than F/F sex). It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting angle, although I&amp;rsquo;m rather concerned that it falls between two fences - there&amp;rsquo;s not enough detail or popular poses for outright porn, but the sex is rather more raw than one might expect in a more mainstream narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, whilst porn might be a very profitable market, it would require a lot of very specific marketing to enter. And many filmmakers tend to like &amp;ldquo;edgy&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; - we&amp;rsquo;ll see if Moviestorm guessed right on their users&amp;rsquo; likely preferences for sex animations. (And indeed if any Moviestorm creators will be brave enough to include non-comedy sex scenes - it&amp;rsquo;s a notoriously hard thing for a storyteller to do).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either case, it would be possible to argue that the Moviestorm team should have thought more, perhaps researched more, produced more animations. But the overall business philosophy that allowed the pack to be created at all mandates against that - this is a high-risk project, and only a company driven by a try-lots-of-things-fast-and-see-what-the-users-like philosophy would have even attempted it. If MS had been inclined to put more detail and more money into the pack, it probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have happened at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be interested to see if it pays off, and if not, if MS tries another sex pack with a different angle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-it-good-for-machinima&#34;&gt;Is it good for Machinima?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were expecting a balanced, non-commital viewpoint here, you may be reading the wrong journalist. Yes, of course it is. This is a sensational move to push the boundaries of Machinima far beyond where they were a few weeks ago. It allows Machinima creators to make films that are more mature, more real, and with more balls. Sure, you might have hated &lt;em&gt;Baise Moi&lt;/em&gt;, but the fact it could be created and shown meant that we could see cinema was a mature artform, not one afraid of real bodies, real sex, real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we want to emulate independent film, or do we want to emulate comic books under the &amp;lsquo;50s Comics Code? If you want the former, I can&amp;rsquo;t see how having a sex pack - even a less than ideal sex pack - available for use can be considered anything less than a huge win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ada Lovelace Day</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/24/ada-lovelace-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 14:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/24/ada-lovelace-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://findingada.com/&#34;&gt;Ada Lovelace Day&lt;/a&gt; again and so, in a combination of genuinely heartfelt celebration and bare-faced self-promotion, here&amp;rsquo;s a link to our article from this time last year, &lt;a href=&#34;http://machinimafordummies.com/articles/2009/03/24/women-who-have-changed-machinima&#34;&gt;Women Who Have Changed Machinima&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anything, women have become even more prominent in Machinima and Anymation over the past twelve months. It&amp;rsquo;s particularly obvious in the more abstract creative communities such as &lt;em&gt;Moviestorm&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;IClone&lt;/em&gt;, but even the communities for supposedly male-oriented games have many prominent female bloggers, movie-makers and celebrity players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s once again raise a glass to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace&#34;&gt;Ada&lt;/a&gt;, and to the women who make our community the vibrant, fascinating and challenging arena it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some amazingly simple storytelling</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/24/some-amazingly-simple-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 12:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/24/some-amazingly-simple-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming from the &amp;ldquo;Rise to Power&amp;rdquo; competition again (what is it with the official Blizzard Machinima competitions that bring out such amazing work? The same thing happened with the Machinima Film Festival), Slashdance&amp;rsquo;s latest effort didn&amp;rsquo;t win anything, but probably should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved &amp;ldquo;Welcome to the Deadmines&amp;rdquo;, but this is its equal in its pure simplicity and emotion. Nearly all shot in-game, too. Love it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper cloth (and hair) simulation in EVE</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/24/proper-cloth-and-hair-simulation-in-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 12:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/24/proper-cloth-and-hair-simulation-in-eve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not very often these days that I get excited by a new graphical advance, but this one got me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proper clothing! Proper hair! At last! (When it eventually turns up)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chorus Lines in WoW!</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/18/chorus-lines-in-wow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 12:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/18/chorus-lines-in-wow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often go on about how Machinima enables scale that you couldn&amp;rsquo;t get in conventional film. Indeed, it isn&amp;rsquo;t too many weeks since I got all excited over my ability to shoot an enormous helicopter shot into a floating castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are other uses for enormous scale than massive landscapes and armies. Uses you might never think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like chorus lines. Big-ass chorus lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a perfect video, but it&amp;rsquo;s bloody good. The fast cutting disguises the limited animation, there&amp;rsquo;s fantastic cutting between World of Warcraft sets and new stuff, and of course the music&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star-studded cast lists - you can have one too</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/11/star-studded-cast-lists-you-can-have-one-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 15:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/03/11/star-studded-cast-lists-you-can-have-one-too/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how far you can get simply by just asking nicely. People will volunteer their time and skills, give you lots of free publicity - even send you money sometimes. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bloodspell.com&#34;&gt;BloodSpell&lt;/a&gt;, for example, would not have been possible without the insanely-enthusiastic fan community that built up around the film, who did some can&amp;rsquo;t-put-a-price-on-it grassroots publicity as well as some can&amp;rsquo;t-quite-believe-it fan remixes and artwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve said all along that, when it comes to casting your movie, if you have a specific actor in mind for a role, it&amp;rsquo;s always worth asking them to do it. Even if they&amp;rsquo;re, y&amp;rsquo;know … famous. You never know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been proven right several times over. Machinima pieces featuring some very famous names have started appearing recently. Bathtub Production&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chroniclesofhumanity.com/castinfo.php?id=9&#34;&gt;The Chronicles Of Humanity&lt;/a&gt; features internet superstar &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Felicia_Day&#34;&gt;Felicia Day&lt;/a&gt; in a minor role, and we hear rumours that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lukeandjoe.com/&#34;&gt;The Aventures Of Luke And Joe&lt;/a&gt; will soon see an appearance by a very well-known actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Strange Company&amp;rsquo;s current project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deathknightlovestory.com/&#34;&gt;Death Knight Love Story&lt;/a&gt;, Hugh has taken the &amp;ldquo;just ask nicely, you never know&amp;rdquo; approach to the extreme. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.strangecompany.org/strangeco/blog_comments/192&#34;&gt;cast list&lt;/a&gt; includes &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anna_Chancellor&#34;&gt;Anna Chancellor&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Four Weddings And A Funeral&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;St Trinian&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_blessed&#34;&gt;Brian Blessed&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;I Claudius&lt;/em&gt;, _The Phantom Menace_1), &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Davenport&#34;&gt;Jack Davenport&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Pirates Of The Carribbean&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Flash Forward&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joanna_Lumley&#34;&gt;Joanna Lumley&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Absolutely Fabulous&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The New Avengers&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machinima (and anymation) has always been inovative, but it&amp;rsquo;s only in the comparitively recent past that the external perception of machinima (and knowledge of its existence!) has become sufficiently strong to attract actors this serious. Fame doesn&amp;rsquo;t automatically imply talent of course, any more than lack of fame implies lack of talent, but the wider world is now starting to realise what we&amp;rsquo;ve known all along: Machinima can produce movies that hold their own against any other type of film-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just goes to show: you never know who&amp;rsquo;ll say &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; until you ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure of bias: I&amp;rsquo;m a creative consultant on Death Knight Love Story, and Hugh is the writer/director. We&amp;rsquo;re as biased as can be, and we&amp;rsquo;re not pretending otherwise!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Oh alright. Flash Gordon, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machinima Festival Feb 20th in SL</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/02/09/machinima-festival-feb-20th-in-sl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 11:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/02/09/machinima-festival-feb-20th-in-sl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We received word of a Machinima festival with seven hours (!) of screenings happening in Second Life next weekend - here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MMIF 2010&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MaMachinima International Festival&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday Feb. 20th , 2010&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MMIF sims (SL) + Planetart, Amsterdam (NL)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;â€˜MMIF 2010&amp;rsquo; is the second edition of an annual film festival in 3D cyberspace with a screening in physical space (&amp;lsquo;RL&amp;rsquo;). A seven hour movie marathon with a two hour afterparty. MMIF 2010 can also be followed on the web via live stream broadcasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MMIF is a celebration of â€˜Machinimaâ€™: a new cinematic art form, created with virtual worlds and video games. On 3D Internet platforms like Second Life, any kind of movie sets can be build for very low costs. The MMIF aims to bring machinima to a wider audience, online â€“ and offline. Machinima artists from all over the world are present in real time at the virtual MMIF Theatre. They present over 50 short films and have talks with other machinimatographers and an international audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audience in Amsterdam can follow the MMIF event projected live on a big screen at the Planetart Medialab Artspace. They can bring their own laptop computers to interact with the show on the big screen. Free wireless Internet and electricity is provided. No entrance fee at Planetart, however tickets are required - reservations must be made via email. Details at &lt;a href=&#34;http://MMIF.org&#34;&gt;http://MMIF.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MMIF is a volunteer-run non-profit collaboration of MaMachinima with Planetart, UrbanResort, Meta.Live.Nu, Pop Art Lab, VMax, Ystreams.TV, Metaworld Broadcasting, MetaMeets, Gallery Fermate, and many volunteers. MMIF 2010 is financed by donations and gifts. Virtual land sponsored by Linden Lab. The MMIF was initiated by the Dutch Film maker Chantal Harvey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MMIF 2010 info, promo video, full programme, live streams, contact and latest updates and changes at &lt;a href=&#34;http://MMIF.org&#34;&gt;http://MMIF.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MMIF 2010 ARTISTS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gala Charron - Ogogoro - Lainy Voom - Draxtor Despres - Bryn Oh - Rohan Fermi - Toxic Menges - Tara Yeats - Phaylen Fairchild - Pooky Amsterdam &amp;amp; Russell (Rosco) Boyd - Poid Mahovlich - CodeWarrior Carling - Evie Fairchild - Graham Miami - Kronos Kirkorian - Osprey Therian - Chaffro Schoonmaker - SaveMe Oh - Dulci Parx - Chatnoir Studios - Paisley Beebe - Rysan Fall - Sol Bartz (phil Rice) - Rocksea Renegade - Cisko Vandeverre â€“ Nitwacket (Pyewacket Bellman) - Chantal Harvey - Lowe Runo - Pia Klaar - Al Peretz - Halden Beaumont - Kolor Fall - Binary Quandry - spyVspy Aeon - Animatechnica - Miles Eleventhauer - Lizsolo Mathilde - Delgado Cinquetti - L1aura Loire - Iono Allen - Pyewacket Kazyanenko - Fort Knight - Luca Lisci - Larkworthy Antfarm - Beans Canning - Gtoon Jun - Tutsy Navarathna - Hadji Ling - Colemarie Soleil - Xineohp Guisse - Lorin Tone - Ian Friar - Suzy Yue - Claus Uriza / Emily Hifeng â€“ Meta Lord, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MMIF 2010 TIMES:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday 20th of February&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:00 CET (= SL 10 am PST) - DOORS OPEN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:00 CET (= SL 11 am PST) - Opening ceremony + Machinima film screenings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;03:00 CET (= SL 6 pm PST) - THE END + After party online in SL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHYSICAL LOCATION:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planetart Medialab Artspace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wibautstraat 150&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1091 GR Amsterdam (NL)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VIRTUAL LOCATION:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MMIF 1, 2, 3, 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second Life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teleport links via &lt;a href=&#34;http://MMIF.org&#34;&gt;http://MMIF.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting news - Runescape Machinima tools</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/01/20/exciting-news-runescape-machinima-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 15:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/01/20/exciting-news-runescape-machinima-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Runescape&amp;rsquo;s the 500lb gorilla in the MMO field right now, boasting arguably more players than World of Warcraft. As such, it&amp;rsquo;s very exciting to hear that the Runescape developers are adding a Machinima tool, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://services.runescape.com/m=devblog/view_post.ws?post_id=78&amp;amp;page;=1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Orb of Oculus&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, to the game - looking forward to seeing what it can do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE - the forum thread on this is up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://services.runescape.com/m=forum/forums.ws?16,17,38,60246965&#34;&gt;29 pages&lt;/a&gt; already. This could spawn quite a lot of new Machinima…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugh&#39;s favourite Machinima films of 2009</title>
      <link>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/01/07/hughs-favourite-machinima-films-of-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 12:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.machinimafordummies.com/2010/01/07/hughs-favourite-machinima-films-of-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Favourite films of 2008 - Hugh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my review of the year yesterday, it&amp;rsquo;s been rather a quiet year for Machinima. Nonetheless, there have been some simply fantastic films released, several of which haven&amp;rsquo;t recieved the kind of widespread acclaim that they deserve. Indeed, I&amp;rsquo;d say all of my favourite films this year deserve to have viewing figures in the hundreds of thousands - yet only one has, and that&amp;rsquo;s only barely over 100,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warrior&amp;rsquo;s Dream

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;



&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good god this piece of World of Warcraft Machinima is good. A very simple tale of a young man - or Tauren, as the case may be - and his dream, it&amp;rsquo;s probably my favourite piece of the year. The editing and cinematography are amongst the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen in any Machinima - incredibly cinematic. The story itself is both surprising, moving and touching - there&amp;rsquo;s even a love story in there, all in 4 minutes or so. Made for the Blizzard Machinima contest this year, it won third place, proving once again that the ones to watch in the Blizz contests are never the winners. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.machinimafordummies.com/articles/2008/07/16/the-demise-fascinating-machinima-hand-drawn-crossover&#34;&gt;The Demise&lt;/a&gt; just missed out on winning last year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film was inspired by Fantasia, and is certainly led by the stunning musical score. It&amp;rsquo;s got absolutely none of the clunks you&amp;rsquo;d normally expect with a WoW movie, and a lot of subtle post-production touches (check out the sunbeam) that really make it stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t play WoW, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to know that the cow people are called Taurens, they&amp;rsquo;re the enemies of the humans in plate armour, and that they can choose, amongst other things, to be either a warrior (sword, shield) or a druid (shapechanging and magic) at the start of the game. That should do you. Now go watch this incredible movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clockwork

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;



&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that&amp;rsquo;s rare in Machinima creation - or anywhere in filmmaking - it&amp;rsquo;s the ability to tell a serious, complex story. On that front, 2009 has been a very good year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clockwork&amp;rsquo;s a Clockwork Orange-inspired dystopian short. I can&amp;rsquo;t really say more than that without spoiling the plot, save to say this - it&amp;rsquo;s possibly the best piece of storytelling in Moviestorm so far. It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect, by any means - it&amp;rsquo;s a bit overwritten in places, the acting occasionally has flaws, and the Moviestorm engine rears its uglier head from time to time with flickering shadows and flat lighting. But its strengths far outweight its weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visual aesthetic and camerawork, for starters, are both fantastic. Iain Friar, the director, has managed to put together a sophsticated, coherent noir visual that puts many broadcast efforts to shame. There&amp;rsquo;s some genuinely iconic shots here, whether you&amp;rsquo;re talking about the droogs heading across the landscape or government meeting shot mostly in moving shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing takes risks - sometimes it gets it wrong, but far more often it gets it right. And the world Iain presents is interesting and complicated. It&amp;rsquo;s not subtle - the future has abolished democracy - but it&amp;rsquo;s moody, it&amp;rsquo;s more complicated than a 10-minute short has any right to manage, and it&amp;rsquo;s compelling. And the lead character&amp;rsquo;s a genuinely memorable figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machinima storytelling that, frankly, puts most of the BBC&amp;rsquo;s efforts this Christmas to shame? More of this, please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shelf Life Part 1

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;



&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And talking of TV-quality storytelling - Shelf Life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an enormous pity that Valve aren&amp;rsquo;t more interested in licensing Source to Machinima creators, because some of the most watchable Machinima of the last few years has used it for its startlingly detailed, expressive characters. Pixel Eyes appear to have picked up the mantle of Lit Fuze, and are running with it to even more interesting places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelf Life, of which only the first part (approximately 16 minutes) is available, appears to be a TV-style drama treading somewhere between The Prisoner and Joss Whedon&amp;rsquo;s Dollhouse. Complex, detailed, with fantastic action sequences, great voice work, and a genuinely intriguing plot involving memory downloading and dubious science, it&amp;rsquo;s moody, atmospheric, and thanks to great Faceposer work, easily as watchable as any other TV or film. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the next part - I want to know what&amp;rsquo;s going on - and I could really see it, if only there was some kind of commercial possibility for the engine, turning into a full-length TV-style series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally it feels a little too slow, and the action sequence in part 2 is a bit protracted. But it&amp;rsquo;s deliberately moody, it&amp;rsquo;s tremendously well-acted and edited, and it fulfils something I&amp;rsquo;m always looking out for - Machinima enabling people who don&amp;rsquo;t have a Hollywood studio to outdo the so-called professionals at their own game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Honourable Mentions

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phil &amp;ldquo;Overman&amp;rdquo; Rice has produced about a million films this year, but I was a particular fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DSQTCm5LrEw&#34;&gt;Blast Supper&lt;/a&gt;, a spot-on parody of Hollywood trailers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lainy Voom&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/2732694&#34;&gt;Fall&lt;/a&gt; really showed off just how beautiful Second Life Machinima can be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;And lastly, an odd choice - Slashdance&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7hrRJkrMfI&#34;&gt;Slashdance vs Ulduar&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s contentless, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a guild promo, but it&amp;rsquo;s just SO damn atmospherically shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>